## Chris Grossman

785 Hennigans Grove Rd. Grove City, OH 43123 (614) 313-6556 chris.r.grossman@gmail.com

### **Career Summary**

A highly talented, skilled IT professional with 17 years of experience in Requirements Gathering, Software and Hardware Architecture, all the way to data modeling/development and software development. Strong communication skills with drive to learn, grow, and understand the problem to develop creative and effective solutions.

#### Technical skills

#### · Skills

- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- In depth knowledge of Classic` (Waterfall) and Iterative (Agile) System Development Life Cycles
- Good organizational and management skills
- Tools: QlikSense, Informatica, SQL Server Management Studio, Oracle SQL Developer, PowerBi, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Jira, MS Teams, Post-Man
- Database: Relational Databases, Data Modeling, SQL, ORACLE, Datawarehouse, Data Vault 2.0
- Languages: SQL, C#, Python, JSON, XML, Java, Java Script

## **Work Experience**

# Senior Business Intelligence Developer: 2015-Present (OhioHealth) Intermediate Intelligence Developer: 2012-2015 (OhioHealth)

QlikSense Administrator/Architect:

- Architect and designed physical server infrastructure environment for multi node Qlik Sense Enterprise environments and performed quarterly upgrade installations.
- Design physical server infrastructure, requirements, developed and executed project plan to migrate Test and Production physical servers to multi-node Virtual Environment.
- Work with customers and vendors to set up 160+ environment interface connections and setting up proper access with security rules using Active Directory.
- Using Python, utilize API process to pull environment statistics and monitoring across multi node environments and storing this information into a SQL database for environment monitoring and standards.

## Lead Business Intelligence Developer/Analyst:

- Lead developer/analyst for projects and support across multiple teams.
- Elicit technical requirements and delivered over 100+ Qlik visual dashboard reporting applications.
- Designed, developed, and automate ETL processes to pull information from multiple data sources: Examples
  - o Epic Clarity, Epic Caboodle, Workday API, Kronos Payroll, PeopleSoft
- Collaborate with business at beginning of pandemic to elicit requirements, design and develop Supply Chain dashboard for calculating burn rate, current stock, and days inventory on hand for COVID-19 supplies and PPE across all OhioHealth locations and distribution centers.
- During Kronos ransomware attack, pulled future approved schedules and emailed managers with a turn around time of one business day.
- Created data model and visual dashboards for Recycling Sustainability board goals across nine waste and recycling vendors. Including Rumpke, Republic, ShredIt, SteriCycle.
- Built a weekly C# program to read through Active Directory and pull associated groups for active employees used for employee security validation and to reduce duplicate or new redundant groups from being created
- Provide on-call and developer/customer technical support.

## Informatica Development:

Create, design and test Informatica PowerCenter mapping and workflows to store 150 Press Ganey aggregated spreadsheets into a Microsoft SQL server database.

- Design Clinical Fact and Dimension tables and assist in the development and monitor of the workflows.
- Collaborate with data team to help troubleshoot and monitor tasks and review mapping
- Collaborate with senior leadership to define requirements and enterprise business definitions for an Emergency Department dashboard door to doc, length of stay, transfers in, transfers out, and discharge efficiency
- Developed a Lab draw site exploration dashboard for understanding the volume, types of specimens, pick up times, and result turn around time
- Collaborated with team to develop a Nurse Predictive hiring model dashboard based on patient volume, turn over rate, transfers, open positions, and recent hires.
- Technical Lead for converting existing SAP universes to current supported format for Information Design Tool (IDT) to provide out of the box self service analytics provided by Epic EMR
- Data Modeling with Enterprise Data Warehouse and Data Vault 2.0
- Technical Lead for building, validation, and publishing of custom SAP Universes tied to EPIC Clarity MS Sql server database and other data sources.
- Create custom solutions using SAP Business Objects by pulling information from different data sources to identify patients who qualify for clinical studies
- Coordinate conversion, upgrade, and testing of SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2013
- Elicit requirements to build a SharePoint form for physician timesheet tracking.

## Specialist, IT Analysis Requirements: 2005-2012 Nationwide Insurance

- Using Visio and modeling tools produced rapid prototyping and screen specs for configuration of Guidewire ClaimCenter
- Responsible for managing interface requirements and non-functional requirements for Guidewire system integration
- Defined technical requirements, mapping, and testing using SoapUI for policy and claims Service Oriented Architecture (SOA).
- Facilitated end-to-end as is analysis and formulate solution and architecture options to assist in business and IT integration decision making
- Responsible for managing detailed application specifications for cross impacted applications
- Handled task of Project Lead for cross application analysis and testing for DB2 upgrade
- Created JBoss logic for policy limit displays for a business common policy view
- Worked with external vendor Safelite Autoglass to implement a batch process solution that decreased project cost by \$200,000
- Created wireframe and screen specs for a common insurance policy and customer view
- Responsible for reviewing external product rate and regulatory work requests for single and cross impact analysis
  - o CPS, CLASS, NAPS, FPS, CLPS, AS400, Allied
  - Loss Cause, Type of Loss, and Coverage Keyword/Coverage Code analysis
- Analyzed and created full end-to-end batch processing diagram for third party vendor processing which was used to decrease analysis time and rewrite the Batch Process (BMP)
- Responsible for modifying business rules for online and batch Data Development System Support(D2S2) components.

### **Education and Certifications**

### De Vry University

- B.S., Computer Information Systems (CIS)
- EPIC Caboodle Data Modeling Certification